A four hundred year old work-in-progress.
Looking for Richard is a documentary film directed by Al Pacino.
Al Pacino's deeply-felt rumination on Shakespeare's significance and relevance to the
modern world through interviews and an in-depth analysis of "Richard III."
Self / Richard III, played by Al Pacino.
Self / Lady Anne, played by Winona Ryder.
Self / Earl of Buckingham, played by Kevin Spacey.
Self / Duke of Clarence, played by Alec Baldwin.
Richmond, played by Aidan Quinn.
Self / King Edward, played by Harris Yulin.
Looking for Richard is a 1996 American documentary film
directed by Al Pacino, in his directorial debut.
It is a hybrid film, including both a filmed performance of selected scenes of William Shakespeare's Richard III and a documentary
element which explores a broader examination of Shakespeare's continuing role and relevance in popular culture.
The film was featured at the Sundance Film Festival in January 1996 and it was
screened in the Un Certain Regard section at the 1996 Cannes Film Festival.
Al Pacino won the Directors Guild of America Award for
Outstanding Directing – Documentaries.
The tone is thought_provoking.